<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Dutch Wave Power</title>
    <link>/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Dutch Wave Power</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Honoured to present our technology to HRH Crown Prince Frederik of Denmark!</title>
      <link>/news/20220623-hrh-crown-prince-frederik-of-denmark-/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/20220623-hrh-crown-prince-frederik-of-denmark-/</guid>
      <description>We were honoured to present our wave energy technology to HRH Crown Prince Frederik of Denmark on 20 June at DMEC (Dutch Marine Energy Centre).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another successful test!</title>
      <link>/news/20210604-successful-tests-at-marin-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/20210604-successful-tests-at-marin-/</guid>
      <description>Over the past two weeks, we have again conducted a series of successful tests at MARIN (Maritime Research Institute Netherlands) during the free basin time for innovative SMEs. The insights gained will accelerate the development of our follow-up prototype, which will soon be deployed in the North Sea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally we can give you a sneak peek</title>
      <link>/news/20201124-sneak-peek/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/20201124-sneak-peek/</guid>
      <description>We have developed an advanced wave energy converter that enables highly reliable conversion of sea and ocean waves into electrical power in an extremely cost effective way. The installation is based on an easy drop &amp;amp; connect principle and in extreme wave conditions the wave energy converter will self protect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A big thanks</title>
      <link>/news/20201117-a-big-thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/20201117-a-big-thanks/</guid>
      <description>A big thanks to Rob van Gils and Ronald Gideonse of Drive Line Systems BV (DLS) for realizing the drive line for our wave energy converter prototype, which we have tested so successfully at Deltares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wave energy potential</title>
      <link>/news/20201001-wave-energy-potential/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/20201001-wave-energy-potential/</guid>
      <description>We are confident we found a way to unlock the enormous wave energy potential. Unfortunately we cannot share the concept with you yet as we are awaiting the patent application. However, we would like to share some facts &amp;amp; figures about wave energy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validation successful!</title>
      <link>/news/20200723-validation-successful-deltares/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/20200723-validation-successful-deltares/</guid>
      <description>Last week, Dutch Wave Power took an important step in unlocking the potential of wave energy. After the first analysis, it can be stated with great certainty that the theoretical model has been validated. In short, the model matches reality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
